Have you ever woken up with a sore throat and blocked nose and wondered if you should take the day off work?
你有没有过早上醒来嗓子疼、鼻子堵，还纠结要不要请假的经历？
Some of us just soldier on, hoping the office environment and banter with work colleagues will perk us up.
有些人会选择硬撑着上班，盼着办公室的氛围和同事间的打趣能让自己精神起来。
Others will make a hot drink, return to bed and have a ‘duvet day’.
还有些人会泡一杯热饮，回到床上，享受一个“被窝休息日”。
But what is the right approach to take?
但到底哪种做法才是正确的呢？
People’s attitude to illness and when to take time off work varies.
人们对于生病以及何时请假的态度各不相同。
Reasons for having a sick day range from a light sniffle to feeling at death’s door.
请假的理由五花八门，从轻微的鼻塞流涕到感觉病入膏肓都有。
And when you have no genuine excuse but just can’t face going into work, it might be time to take a sickie.
而当你没什么正当理由，只是实在不想上班的时候，或许就该“装病请假”了。
A survey of British workers by YouGov found 15% of workers who admitted making up an illness to get a day off used a migraine as their excuse.
舆观调查公司针对英国职场人士的一项调查显示，在承认过编造病情请假的人中，有15%会用偏头痛当借口。
But what about a common cold – is having one a genuine enough reason for missing work?
但普通感冒呢？它算得上是旷工的正当理由吗？
This is something Ian Shoesmith explored for the BBC.
伊恩·休史密斯为英国广播公司探讨了这个问题。
He looked into “the murky moral maze” that brought together employment law, ethics and public health.
他深入研究了这个交织着劳动法、道德规范和公共卫生的“晦暗的道德迷宫”。
He spoke to Rachel Suff, senior policy adviser at the Chartered Institute of Personnel and Development, who said "If you are really not well and your symptoms mean you are not going to be productive, it's better to go off sick.
他采访了英国特许人事与发展协会的高级政策顾问蕾切尔·萨夫，对方表示：“如果你真的身体不适，而且症状已经影响到工作效率，那最好还是请假。
You're also not spreading your germs around the workplace."
这样也不会把病菌传染给同事。”
But Ian also found that catching a cold from someone could help build up your immune system and be good for long-term health.
但伊恩也发现，被他人传染感冒，其实有助于增强自身免疫系统，对长远健康有好处。
However it can depend on what type of cold it is.
不过，这也取决于感冒的类型。
Of course, deciding whether to take time off to recuperate from a cold may depend on where you work.
当然，感冒后要不要请假休养，可能还取决于你的工作环境。
Hayley Johnson, an employment lawyer at Slater and Gordon, told the BBC that sometimes members of staff feel obliged to work when they are sick "because they fear the mountain of work will just keep piling up" for when they return.
斯莱特和戈登律师事务所的劳工律师海莉·约翰逊告诉英国广播公司，有时候员工生病也会硬撑着上班，“因为他们担心休假回来后，工作会堆积如山”。
But if an employee is feeling under the weather but well enough to work, a solution could be to work from home.
但如果员工只是有些不舒服，身体状况还允许工作，那居家办公会是一个不错的选择。
As a cure for a common cold is still a long way off, having this lurgy as an excuse for a day off work is not to be sneezed at!
既然彻底治愈普通感冒的方法还遥遥无期，那借着这场小感冒请一天假，也是值得考虑的一件事！